So my name is Taylor Wilson.
إسمي تايلور ويلسون
I am 17 years old
وعمري 17 سنة
and I am a nuclear physicist,
وأنا عالم فيزياء نووية،
which may be a little hard to believe, but I am.
مما قد يكون صعب التصديق، لكني كذلك.
And I would like to make the case
وأودّ أن أقدم البرهان
that nuclear fusion
على أنّ الإندماج النووي
will be that point,
سيكون تلك النقطة
that the bridge that T. Boone Pickens talked about
التي يمكن للجسر الذي تحدث عنه تي بون بيكنز
will get us to.
أن يوصلنا إليها.
So nuclear fusion is our energy future.
إذاً فالاندماج النووي هو مستقبل طاقتنا.
And the second point,
والنقطة الثانية،
making the case that kids can really change the world.
هي تقديم برهان على أن اليافعين يمكنهم بالفعل تغيير العالم
So you may ask --
فقد تتسائلون --
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
You may ask me,
قد تسألونني،
well how do you know what our energy future is?
كيف تعرف ماهو مستقبل طاقتنا؟
Well I built a fusion reactor
حسناً, لقد بنيت مفاعلاً إندماجياً
when I was 14 years old.
عندما كان عمري 14 سنة
That is the inside of my nuclear fusion reactor.
هذا ما بداخل المفاعل النووي الاندماجي خاصتي.
I started building this project
لقد بدأت ببناء هذا المشروع
when I was about 12 or 13 years old.
عندما كان عمري 12 أو 13 سنة.
I decided I wanted to make a star.
لقد قررت أنني أريد أن أصنع نجمة.
Now most of you are probably saying,
محتمل أن معظمكم يقول:
well there's no such thing as nuclear fusion.
لا يوجد ما يسمى بالإندماج النووي.
I don't see any nuclear power plants with fusion energy.
لا أرى مصانع طاقة نووية تعمل بفعل الطاقة الإندماجية.
Well it doesn't break even.
حسناً، إنه لا يعمل بكفاءة.
It doesn't produce more energy out than I put in,
وهو لا يولّد طاقة أكثر من الداخلة إليه،
but it still does some pretty cool stuff.
لكن له بعض المزايا الفريدة.
And I assembled this in my garage,
وقد جمّعت هذا في مرآبي,
and it now lives in the physics department
وهو الآن يقبع في شعبة الفيزياء
of the University of Nevada, Reno.
بجامعة نيفادا، رينو.
And it slams together deuterium,
وهي تصدم الديوتيريوم ببعضه,
which is just hydrogen with an extra neutron in it.
الذي هو هيدروجين يحوي نيتروناً إضافياً.
So this is similar to the reaction
لذا فهو يشبه تفاعل
of the proton chain that's going on inside the Sun.
سلسلة البروتون بداخل الشمس.
And I'm slamming it together so hard
أقوم بصدمها مع بعضها بقوة
that that hydrogen fuses together,
بحيث يندمج الهيدروجين مع بعضه،
and in the process it has some byproducts,
ولهذه العملية بعض النواتج الثانوية
and I utilize those byproducts.
وأقوم بالاستفادة من تلك النواتج.
So this previous year,
في العام الماضي،
I won the Intel International Science and Engineering Fair.
فزت بجائزة شركة إنتل العالمية للعلوم والهندسة.
I developed a detector that replaces the current detectors
فقد طوّرت كاشفاً يستبدل الكواشف الحالية
that Homeland Security has.
التي تملكها وكالة أمن الوطن.
For hundreds of dollars,
مقابل مئات الدولارات,
I've developed a system that exceeds the sensitivity
قمت ببناء نظام يفوق بحساسيته
of detectors that are hundreds of thousands of dollars.
الكواشف التي تكلف مئات الآلوف من الدولارات.
I built this in my garage.
صنعت ذلك في مرآبي.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
And I've developed a system
وقد طوّرت نظاماً
to produce medical isotopes.
لإنتاج النظائر الطبية.
Instead of requiring multi-million-dollar facilities
عوضاً عن الحاجة لمنشآت بملايين الدولارات
I've developed a device that, on a very small scale,
قمت بتطوير جهاز يستطيع على نطاق صغير جدا
can produce these isotopes.
أن ينتج هذه النظائر.
So that's my fusion reactor in the background there.
ذاك هو مفاعلي الإندماجي في الخلفية.
That is me at the control panel
وهذا أنا عند لوحة التحكم
of my fusion reactor.
الخاصة بمفاعلي الإندماجي.
Oh, by the way, I make yellowcake in my garage,
وبالمناسبة، أصنع كعكاً أصفر في مرآبي،
so my nuclear program is as advanced as the Iranians.
لذا فبرنامجي النووي متقدم بقدر برنامج الإيرانيين.
So maybe I don't want to admit to that.
ربما لا أريد أن أعترف بذلك.
This is me at CERN in Geneva, Switzerland,
هذا أنا في مختبر سيرن في جنيف، سويسرا،
which is the preeminent particle physics laboratory in the world.
والذي هو أبرز مختبر لفيزياء الجسيمات في العالم.
And this is me with President Obama,
وهذا أنا مع الرئيس أوباما،
showing him my Homeland Security research.
أعرض عليه بحثي الخاص بالأمن الوطني.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
So in about seven years
إذاً خلال سبع سنوات
of doing nuclear research,
من القيام بالأبحاث النووية،
I started out with a dream
بدأت بحلم
to make a "star in a jar," a star in my garage,
لصنع "نجمة في جرة"، نجمة في مرآبي،
and I ended up meeting the president
وانتهي بي المطاف بمقابلة الرئيس
and developing things that I think can change the world,
وتطوير أشياء أعتقد أنّ بإمكانها تغيير العالم
and I think other kids can too.
وأعتقد أن بقية اليافعين يمكنهم أيضاً فعل ذلك.
So thank you very much.
شكراً جزيلاً لكم
(Applause)
(تصفيق)